<!DOCTYPE Article PUBLIC "-//GNOME//DTD DocBook PNG Variant V1.1//EN"[
<!ENTITY version "1.0.53">
<!-- Template Version: 1.0.1 (do not remove this line) -->
]>


<article id="index">

 <artheader>
  <title>GNOME Tetravex Manual</title>
  <copyright>
   <year>2001</year>
   <holder>Rob Bradford </holder>
  </copyright>

  <legalnotice id="legalnotice"> 
   <para> 
     Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or
     modify this document under the terms of the <citetitle>GNU Free
     Documentation License</citetitle>, Version 1.1 or any later version
     published by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant
     Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts. You may
     obtain a copy of the <citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
     License</citetitle> from the Free Software Foundation by visiting
     <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org" type="http">their Web site</ulink>
     or by writing to: Free Software Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place -
     Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307, USA.
   </para>
   <para>
     Many of the names used by companies to distinguish their products
     and services are claimed as trademarks. Where those names appear in
     any GNOME documentation, and those trademarks are made aware to the
     members of the GNOME Documentation Project, the names have been
     printed in caps or initial caps.
   </para>
  </legalnotice>

  <releaseinfo>This is version 1.0 of GNOME Tetravex manual.  </releaseinfo>
 </artheader>

 <sect1 id="intro">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>
    <application>GNOME Tetravex</application> is a simple puzzle where
    pieces must be positioned so that the same numbers are touching each other.
    Your game is timed, these times are stored in a system-wide scoreboard.
  </para>
    
  <para> 
    To run <application>GNOME Tetravex</application>, select
    <menuchoice>
     <guisubmenu>Games</guisubmenu> 
     <guimenuitem>Gnotravex</guimenuitem> 
    </menuchoice>
    from the <guimenu>Main Menu</guimenu>, or type 
    <command>gnotravex</command> on the command line.
  </para>

  <para>
    <application>GNOME Tetravex</application> is included in the
    <filename>gnome-games</filename> package, which is part of the GNOME
    desktop environment. This document describes version
    &version; of <application>GNOME Tetravex</application>.
  </para>
 </sect1>

 <sect1 id="usage"> 
  <title>Playing GNOME Tetravex</title>

  <para>
    <application>GNOME Tetravex</application> is a simple puzzle
    game, this section covers how to play the game.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="mainwin">
   <title>Basic usage</title>
   <sect3 id="playing">
    <title>Playing the game</title> 
    <para> 
      Starting <application>GNOME Tetravex</application> opens the 
      <interface>Main window</interface>, shown in 
      <xref linkend="mainwindow-fig">. The window is divided into two boxes.
      The right hand side contains a box containing the pieces you have yet
      to place and the left hand box is where you arrange the pieces.
     </para>

     <figure id="mainwindow-fig">
      <title>GNOME Tetravex Main Window</title> 
      <screenshot>
       <screeninfo>GNOME Tetravex Main Window</screeninfo> 
       <graphic fileref="figures/gnotravex_mainwindow" format="png" srccredit="ME"></graphic>
      </screenshot> 
     </figure>

     <para> 
       You can start playing the game immediately, the time starts when you
       move the first piece into a position. You may restart the game by
       doing
       <menuchoice>
	<guisubmenu>File</guisubmenu>
	<guimenuitem>New game</guimenuitem>
       </menuchoice>
	<xref linkend="playing-fig">
	</para>
      <figure id="playing-fig">
       <title>A GNOME Tetravex Game</title> 
       <screenshot> 
        <screeninfo>A GNOME Tetravex Game</screeninfo> 
        <graphic fileref="figures/gnotravex_game" format="png" srccredit="ME"></graphic> 
       </screenshot>
      </figure>
     <para>
       The tiles are divided into four, you must position them so that only
       two numbers that are the same are next to each other. The game wil not
       let you position the tiles so that different numbers are next to each
       other. You position the pieces by dragging them from their current
       position either in the right hand box or the main box to their new
       position. These moves are not permanent and can be readily reversed.
       You may also move the pieces by using the commands:
	<menuchoice>
	 <guisubmenu>Move</guisubmenu>
         <guimenuitem>Left/Right/Up/Down</guimenuitem>
	</menuchoice>
     </para>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 id="winning">
     <title>Winning the game</title> 
     <para>
       The game is completed when you have positioned all the squares in the
       right positions. When you have completed the game you are shown your
       ranking in the high scores table (if you get a high enough score), 
       like this one.
     </para>
    </sect3>

  </sect2>
 </sect1>
	
 <sect1 id="prefs"> 
  <title>Customization</title> 
  <para> 
    Customization is relativly limited, you can change the size of the grid
by 
    <menuchoice>
     <guimenu>Settings</guimenu> 
     <guimenuitem>2 x 2 etc.</guimenuitem>
    </menuchoice>.  
  </para>

 </sect1>

 <sect1 id="bugs">
  <title>Known Bugs and Limitations</title> 
  <para> 
    Of course not, its perfect!
  </para> 
 </sect1>

 <sect1 id="authors"> 
  <title>Authors</title> 
  <para> 
    <application>GNOME Tetravex</application> was written by Lars Rydlinge
    (<email>lars.rydlinge@hig.se</email>). <application>GNOME
    Tetravex</application> is part of the gnome-games package which is a core
    GNOME package, please visit the 
    <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org" type="http">GNOME Web page</ulink> 
     for details. Please send all comments, suggestions, and bug reports to the   
    <ulink url="http://bugs.gnome.org" type="http">GNOME bug tracking
    database</ulink>. 
    (Instructions for submitting bug reports can be found
    <ulink url="http://bugs.gnome.org/Reporting.html" type="http">
    on-line</ulink>.) You can also use <application>Bug Report
    Tool</application> (<command>bug-buddy</command>), available in the
    <guisubmenu>Utilities</guisubmenu> submenu of <guimenu>Main
    Menu</guimenu>, for submitting bug reports.
  </para>

  <para> 
    This manual was written by Rob Bradford
    (<email>rob@funky-penguin.co.uk</email>). Please send all comments and
    suggestions regarding this manual to the <ulink
    url="http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gdp" type="http">GNOME
    Documentation Project</ulink> by sending an email to
    <email>docs@gnome.org</email>. You can also add your comments online by
    using the <ulink url="http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gdp/doctable/"
    type="http">GNOME Documentation Status Table</ulink>.
  </para>

  <!-- For translations: uncomment this:
  <para>
    Latin translation was done by ME (<email>MYNAME@MYADDRESS</email>). 
    Please send all comments and suggestions regarding this translation to
    SOMEWHERE.
  </para>
   -->

 </sect1>

 <sect1 id="license"> 
  <title>License</title> 
  <para> 
    This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it 
    under the terms of the <citetitle>GNU General Public License</citetitle> 
    as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the 
    License, or (at your option) any later version.
  </para>
  <para>
    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but
    WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    <citetitle>GNU General Public License</citetitle> for more details.
  </para>
  <para>
    A copy of the <citetitle>GNU General Public License</citetitle> is
    included as an appendix to the <citetitle>GNOME Users
    Guide</citetitle>.  You may also obtain a copy of the <citetitle>GNU
    General Public License</citetitle> from the Free Software Foundation by
    visiting <ulink url="http://www.fsf.org" type="http">their Web
    site</ulink> or by writing to 
    <address>
      Free Software Foundation, Inc.  
     <street>59 Temple Place</street>
     - Suite 330 
     <city>Boston</city>, 
     <state>MA</state>
     <postcode>02111-1307</postcode> 
     <country>USA</country> 
    </address>
  </para> 
 </sect1>
</article>
